boaterexam.com 2019-02-28

# U.S. Privacy Policy | BOATERexam.com®

##  Our Privacy Commitment

This version in effect since May 16th, 2007.

At BOATERexam.com® we know how important it is to protect your personal information. Whether you are shopping with us online or in person we want to make every customer experience safe and secure. In keeping with that goal, we have developed this Privacy Policy to outline our guidelines for the collection and use of personal information.

###  Who is BOATERexam.com®?

BOATERexam.com® is the operating name of Boater Exam America, Inc., a leading provider of safe boater education across North America. This privacy policy applies to Boater Exam America, Inc. and all of its named operations and divisions.

###  What Information does BOATERexam.com® Collect and How is it Used?

At BOATERexam.com®, we collect two types of information: personal information and non-personal information.

With your consent we may use your personal information for a number of different purposes, for example to:

  * fulfill requests for products, services or information; 
  * provide customer services; 
  * administer contests or promotions; 
  * offer new products and services; 
  * measure and improve the effectiveness of our Web Sites or our marketing endeavors; and 
  * tailor our online or on-site offerings to your preferences. 

We may also collect and summarize customer information in a format that no longer identifies the individual for statistical purposes.

Personal information typically includes your name, address, phone number, and e-mail address. You can always choose not to provide us with any of your personal information. However, if you make this choice we may not be able to provide you with the product, service, or information that you requested.

Non-personal information does not identify you as an individual. For example, we may ask you for your postal code to assist us with planning our advertising and promotional efforts.

**Your Implied Consent**

In some cases, your consent is implied if we ask you to provide personal information with a stated purpose. For example, we can only deliver the product you have purchased if you provide us with your address and phone number.

**Your Express Consent**

In other cases, we will ask you to give your express consent to use your personal information to advise you of products or services that may be of interest. You always have the opportunity to "opt out" of having your information used for this purpose.

**Withdrawing Your Consent**

If you have "opted in" or subscribed to one of our newsletters or mailing lists, we will always provide you the opportunity to "opt out" or unsubscribe. For example, each e-mail we send you will tell you how to decline further e-mail.

###  Information BOATERexam.com® Collects from You

Listed here are some examples of the ways that we collect information about you and how we use it.

**On-Site Purchases**

When you purchase a BOATERexam.com® product or service, you may need to provide us with contact and payment information (such as credit card information) so that we can process your request. Examples where we need contact information include delivery of products, mailing of your Boater Education Card, and rebate requests. If we collect this information, we may also ask for your consent to use this information to send you promotional information on products and services.

**Our Web Sites**

While using our Web Sites, you may be asked to voluntarily provide certain personal information (such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, or credit card information). We use this information to complete your transaction and to apply for access to certain special features and functions of the Web Sites. If you choose not to provide requested personal information, you will not be able to use certain features of the Web Sites and you will not be able to engage in transactions through the Web Sites.

With any of the services on our Web Sites, we may also use your personal information to contact and correspond with you and to respond to your inquiries. With your consent, we may send to you, from time to time, email or other communications regarding goods or services we believe will interest you.

All references to our Web Site in this Policy means www.BOATERexam.com®/usa/

**Sign-Up for Newsletters or Updates**

BOATERexam.com® also offers an e-newsletter. You can choose to subscribe by visiting our Web Sites or when visiting us at a special event. To enroll, we will collect your contact information (such as name and e-mail address). This information will only be used to send you the newsletter. 

**Participate in a Contest, Promotion, or Survey**

From time to time, we may run contests, promotions, or surveys. If you participate, you may be asked for contact information as well as additional optional survey information (for example, product preferences). Information from contest entries will be used to contact you if you win. We may also summarize survey information in a manner that no longer identifies the contest entrants for analysis, but will not share personal information from entries. All contests are subject to rules that will be available with each particular contest.

###  Information BOATERexam.com® collects Automatically

Like many other Web sites, we automatically collect certain non-personal information regarding Web site users that does not identify you. Examples include the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer, the IP address of your Internet Service Provider, the date and time you access the Web Site, the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to the Web Site, the operating system you are using, the sections of the Web Site you visit, the Web Site pages read and images viewed, and the content you download from the Web Site.

This non-personal information is used for Web Site and system administration purposes and to improve the Web Site.

**Cookies**

The Web Site uses "cookies", a technology that installs a small amount of information on a Web Site user's computer to permit the Web Site to recognize future visits using that computer. Cookies enhance the convenience and use of the Web Site. For example, the information provided through cookies is used to recognize you as a previous user of the Web Site (so you do not have to enter your billing information every time), to offer personalized Web page content and information for your use, to track your activity at the Web Site, to respond to your needs, and to otherwise facilitate your Web Site experience. You may choose to decline cookies if your browser permits, but doing so may affect your use of the Web Site and your ability to access certain features of the Web Site or engage in transactions through the Web Site.

The Web Site uses third party display advertising networks to collect visitor data and then serve targeted display ads back to these visitors when browsing other web sites. Our partners use technology such as cookies and web beacons to collect this data. For more information or to opt-out of this type of advertising, please visit [www.adroll.com](http://www.adroll.com/about/privacy).

**Tracking Information**

We may use non-personal information to compile tracking information reports regarding Web Site user demographics, Web Site traffic patterns, and Web Site purchases, and then provide those reports to advertisers and others. None of the tracking information in the reports can be connected to the identities or other personal information of individual users. We may also link tracking information with personal information voluntarily provided by Web Site users. Once such a link is made, all of the linked information is treated as personal information and will be used and disclosed only in accordance with this Policy.

###  Links to Other Web Sites

Our Web Site may contain links to other Web sites or Internet resources. When you click on one of those links you are contacting another Web site or Internet resource. BOATERexam.com® has no responsibility or liability for or control over those other Web sites or Internet resources or their collection, use and disclosure of your personal information.

We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those other sites to learn how they collect and use information about you.

###  Does BOATERexam.com® Disclose the Information it Collects?

BOATERexam.com® does not sell your personal information. However we may share your information with third parties acting on our behalf or as permitted or required by law.

###  Disclosure to Service Providers

BOATERexam.com® may share your personal information with certain service providers in order to provide products and services to you, to verify and validate information, and to address customer service matters. Examples of service providers include those suppliers who print your Boater Education Card. To reduce the risk of fraud or misuse of personal information, BOATERexam.com® may also verify your personal information, including but not limited to your address and credit card information, with third party service providers.

We will use reasonable efforts to ensure that your personal information is used in a manner that is consistent with this Policy. If you do not wish us to provide your personal information to those service providers, we may be unable to process your transaction.

###  Legal Disclosure

BOATERexam.com® may disclose your information as permitted or required to by law; for example:

  * to a government institution or other person or entity that has asserted its lawful authority to obtain the information; 
  * where we have reasonable grounds to believe the information could be useful in the investigation of unlawful activity; 
  * to comply with a subpoena or warrant or an order made by a court, person or entity with jurisdiction to compel the production of information; 
  * to comply with court rules regarding the production of records and information; and 
  * to our legal counsel. 

###  How does BOATERexam.com® Protect My Information?

The security of your personal information is a high priority. We maintain appropriate safeguards and current security standards to protect your personal information, whether recorded on paper or captured electronically, against unauthorized access, disclosure, or misuse.

Although we cannot take responsibility for any theft, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, loss, alteration or destruction of data by a third party, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences.

###  How Can I Verify My Information?

You can check your information to verify, update, or correct it, and to have any obsolete information removed. 

You can also ask to review any of the information that we have retained, how we have used it, and to whom we have disclosed it at any time by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) Subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law, and provided we can authenticate your identity, you will be given reasonable access to your personal information, and will be entitled to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and to have it amended as appropriate.

You can also ask us to change your preferences regarding how we use or disclose your information, or let us know that you do not wish to receive any further communication from us.

###  When is My Information Removed?

We keep your information only as long as we need it for the products and services you're using and for a reasonable time thereafter or to meet any legal requirements. We have retention standards that meet these requirements. We destroy your information when it is no longer needed, or we remove your personally identifiable information.

You can also request that we remove your information from our records. Subject to our requirements for continued retention of your information, for example, for billing, audit, or warranty purposes, we will make every reasonable effort to honour your request.

###  Children's Online Privacy Protection Act 

BOATERexam.com® complies with the Federal Trade Commission's COPPA Act. Parents or legal guardians of any students may contact BOATERexam.com® regarding any personal information or the privacy policy for your children. Upon verifiable request, BOATERexam.com® will correct, add or remove any personal information on the student. 

###  How Can I Contact BOATERexam.com®?

BOATERexam.com® is responsible for all personal information under its control. If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about the privacy policies please contact us at the below:

**Boater Exam America Inc.**  
Attention: Privacy Manager  
203-1568 Carling ave.  
Ottawa, ON K1Z 7M4  
CANADA  
1-866-764-2628  
[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

We will respond to your request or investigate your concern as quickly as we can.

###  Will this Privacy Policy Change?

To accommodate changes in our service, the technology, and legal developments, this Policy may change over time. We may add, change, or remove portions of this Policy when we feel it is appropriate to do so. Whenever we update this Policy we will change the date on the Policy to indicate when the changes were made.
